Guide to the Christopher Knowles Papers, 1973-2015 (bulk 1973-1990) MSS.414
Fales Library and Special Collections
Christopher Knowles Papers
1973-2015
1973-1990
Fales Library and Special Collections
Wilson, Robert 1941-
Christopher Knowles
Johns, Jasper, 1930-
Glass, Philip
Cage, John
Knowles, Christopher
MSS.414
22.5 Linear Feet in 24 boxes and 2 record cartons.
The Christopher Knowles Papers contain material relating to the personal and professional life of visual and performing artist Christopher Knowles. Born in Brooklyn, NY in 1959, Knowles connected with avant-garde artist Robert Wilson at age 14, after Wilson heard a tape of Knowles speaking the words of his poem "Emily Likes the TV." They collaborated on many performances pieces, most notably "Einstein on the Beach." Knowles has performed internationally and has had his artwork exhibited in both joint and solo shows at galleries including, but not limited to, the Holly Solomon Gallery, Gavin Brown's Enterprise and the Museum of Modern Art. He continues to live and work in New York City.
Separated Materials
Books included in this collection have been removed and will be cataloged in BobCat. They will be available via a BobCat search for "Christopher Knowles."
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 14 series:
SERIES I: Journals
SERIES II: Performance
Subseries A: Performance with Christopher Knowles
Subseries B: Performance without Christopher Knowles
SERIES III: Exhibitions
SERIES IV: Art
SERIES V: Correspondence
SERIES VI: Press
SERIES VII: Personal
SERIES VIII: Photographs
Subseries A: Photographs
Subseries B: Slides
SERIES IX: Sound recordings
SERIES X: Video recordings
SERIES XI: Data storage
SERIES XII: Sound and Video Preservaion
SERIES XIII: 2016 Accession SERIES XIV: Books
The material is arranged chronologically with the exceptions of Series II, Series IX, Series X, and Series XIV which are all arranged alphabetically. Series XIII has not been arranged by an archivist, and remains in the order in which it was received. Original order, as dictated by Knowles and a consulting archivist, was preserved wherever possible. Oversize material is arranged at the end, under the corresponding series number. There is also oversize material in map case 2D. Video and sound recordings, as well as the data storage, were left in the original order as received from the donor and given ID numbers.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Brooklyn in 1959, Christopher Knowles is an artist who works within a variety of mediums including performance, poetry, paintings and what are called "typings," visual pieces created using a typewriter, most commonly with the letter "c" for "Christopher". In 1973, at the age of 14, Knowles was approached by avant-garde theater director and artist Robert Wilson, who had heard a tape of Knowles reciting his piece, "Emily Loves the TV" and hoped to collaborate with Knowles. Knowles went, with his parents, to a performance of Wilson's "The Life and Times of Joseph Stalin," where Wilson brought Knowles on stage to perform what would become Knowles' piece, "Emily Likes the TV." This was the beginning of a long friendship which would lead them to collaborate many times over the years, most famously in 1976 on "Einstein on the Beach," which was also in collaboration with composer Philip Glass and choreographer Lucinda Childs. Knowles lived in Wilson's SoHo loft and art studio for a time, working with the Byrd Hoffman School of Byrd's, Wilson's art and performance collective. Other collaborative work included performances with Cindy Lubar and Richard Kostelanetz.
Knowles has had a number of joint and solo shows of his visual art at the Kitchen, the Holly Solomon Gallery, the Byrd Hoffman Studio, Gavin Brown's Enterprise, the Museum of Modern Art, ICA Philadelphia and the Louvre. The Museum of Modern Art acquired some of Knowles' Typings in 2013. Knowles continues to live and work in New York City and travels widely to perform.
Scope and Content
The collection contains material pertaining to Knowles professional work as an artist. However, much of that work was done as a young adolescent, which is reflected throughout the collection. His journals are a repository for his artwork as well as his personal life and contain reflections of his exhibited or performed art. There is material relating to the many performances in which he took part, including programs, press, reviews, source material, scripts, photographs and publicity. Some of the performances include "Einstein on the Beach," "The $ Value of Man," "A Letter for Queen Victoria," "Dialog/Curious George," and "Parzival." Many of these were collaborations with Robert Wilson. In addition to the paper material related to his performances, there are video and sound recordings of shows, as well as recordings that Knowles used as a part of his performances.
Knowles produced a large portfolio of paintings and drawings in addition to his performance art. The collection includes material documenting his exhibitions, both domestic and international, including press, gallery cards, exhibit catalogs and correspondence. There are photographs of his exhibited work, as well as slides, in addition to marker, pen and crayon drawings. Notably, Knowles created what are called "Typings," made with a typewriter and most commonly using the letter "c" to create designs and images. This collection contains quite a few typings, as well as typewritten poetry and some prose.
Correspondence includes letters, cards and postcards both sent and received by Knowles. Notable correspondence includes Jasper Johns, John Cage, Robert Wilson and Cindy Lubar. Knowles also designed and created a large number of birthday and father's day cards, as well as invitations to his shows and his own birthday parties.
Photographs include many taken of Knowles and his family, as well of images of his art. There are photographs of performances and rehearsals, international exhibits and shows, in addition to family vacations and his home in Brooklyn. There is a small amount of material relating to Knowles' personal life, including medical and educational information and resumes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Christopher Knowles Papers were donated by Christopher Knowles in October of 2014. The accession number associated with this donation is 2014.414. The 2016 Accretion to the Christopher Knowles Papers was received in February of 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.012.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Related Materials
Judson Memorial Church Archive
Medical records.; Avant-garde (Music); Avant-garde theater.; Avant-garde poetry.; Performance art.; Performance artists.; Painters -- United States.; Paintings (visual works); Theater |z Germany.; Germany.; Performance art -- New York (State) -- New York.; Performance art -- United States.; crayons (drawing material); Drawings; Experimental theater.; Theater -- New York (State) -- New York.; Wilson, Robert 1941-; Johns, Jasper, 1930-; Glass, Philip; Cage, John
- Series I: Journals, 274420
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically, with undated material at the back.
  Scope and Content
  This series contains journals and sketchbooks filled by Christopher Knowles. Many contain work referencing larger complete artworks, such as "Curious George," which was a collaboration with Robert Wilson. Done mostly in marker or pen, the journals also include many of Knowles "Top Ten" song lists, which he created listening to WABC DJs. Occasionally, the journals contain typewritten text that was then tapped into the blank book. There are also two books created by Knowles as a young child, with the aid of a parent, using text, drawing and photographs. Additionally, a few of the journals include additions by collaborator Cindy Lubar and Robert Wilson.
  - School Workbook, 1971-1972; 274461 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The 6 People in the Knowles Family, February 1973; 274462 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The New York by Chris Knowles, February 1973; 274463 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Book of People..., March 1973; 274464 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Book About Spring, Summer, Fall and Winter, March 1973; 274465 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The 11 Chapters, April 1973; 274466 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A B C D E F G H I..., May 1981; 274467 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chris' Math Book, undated; 274468 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - [Cindy Lubar and Christopher Knowles], undated; 274469 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - English, undated; 274470 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mr. Bojangles, undated; 274471 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 9 Chapters by Chris Knowles [part] 1, undated; 274472 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 9 Chapters by Chris Knowles [part] 2, undated; 274473 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Since Three Years..., undated; 274474 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II: Performance, 274421
  This series is arranged alphabetically, with multiple occurances of the same performance arranged chronologically. Subseries A contains material for performances to which Knowles contributed directly. Subseries B contains material relating to performances in which Knowles was not immediately involved.
  This series contains material relating to Christopher Knowles' performance art. This includes programs, photographs, source material and posters, as well as some correspondence and press. Many of these performances were written by or originally conceived by others, most prominently Robert Wilson, but Knowles often contributed text or set design, if he was not performing in the piece itself.
  - Subseries A: Performances with Christopher Knowles, 274424
    - 2 Lips and Dancers and Space, November 2004 - June 2005; 274506 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 70 Angels on the Facade, 1998; 274507 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - $ Value of Man assorted material, 1974-1976; 274508 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - $ Value of Man program, 1975; 274509 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - $ Value of Man supporting material, c. 1975; 274510 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - $ Value of Man loose material for program, 1975, undated; 274511 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - $ Value of Man libretto, undated; 274512 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Alice Through the Looking Glass, 1993; 274513 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Aquilarco, 1998; 274514 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Byrd Hoffman Performance Calendar, March 1975; 274515 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Christopher Knowles Invitations to Performances, undated; 274516 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Contact Quarterly Benefit Performances, April 1978; 274517 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Contract for Scenarios with Richard Kostelanetz, 1980; 274518 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Nametapes" Copyright Registration, November 29, 1979; 274519 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - The Days Before, June 1999 - July 1999; 274520 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dialog/Curious George Reviews [1 of 2], 1980; 274521 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Dialog/Curious George Reviews, 1980; 274522 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Dialog/Curious George Stagebill and Flyer, 1980; 274523 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Dialog/Network original typescripts, 1978; 274524 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Buffalo Dreams, undated; 274525 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Einstein on the Beach Libretto, 1976; 274526 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Einstein on the Beach Lincoln Center Program, 1976; 274527 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Einstein on the Beach New York Times Review, November 23, 1976; 274528 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Einstein on the Beach Open Rehearsal, 1976; 274529 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Einstein on the Beach Book and BAM program, 1984, undated; 274530 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Einstein on the Beach BAM program, 1992; 274531 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Einstein on the Beach at McCarter Theater, July 1992; 274532 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Einstein on the Beach at the Barbican and Opera Orchestre National, 2012; 274534 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Einstein on the Beach at BAM and Ann Arbor, 2012; 274535 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Emily Likes the TV script, 1976; 274536 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Emily Likes the TV unbound script, 1976-1977; 274537 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Emily Likes the TV photographs, 1976-1977; 274538 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Emily Likes the TV photographs and contact sheets, 1977, undated; 274539 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Emily Likes the TV and $ Value of man typescripts from workshop, 1989, undated; 274540 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Everyday Business photographs and contact sheets [1 of 2], 1976, undated; 274541 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Everyday Business photographs and contact sheets [2 of 2], 1976, undated; 274542 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Everyday Business Flyer, 1979; 274543 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Everyday Business in the SoHo Weekly News, April 19, 1979; 274544 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Everyday Buesiness photographs, undated; 274545 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Get Wreck at The Kitchen, 1978; 274546 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Global and Collection, 1982; 274547 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Grace for Grace production notes, undated; 274548 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - A Letter for Queen Victoria Book, 1974-1975; 274549 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Queen Victoria press and program, 1974-1975; 274550 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin, 1973; 274551 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin photographs, undated; 274552 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - A Mad Man, A Mad Dog, 1974; 274553 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - My Show invitations, undated; 274554 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Other Rooms, Other Voices, undated; 274555 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Parzival in Hamburg supporting material, 1987-1988; 274556 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Parzival book [in German], 1987; 274557 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Parzival script, 1987; 274558 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Parzival program at Thalia Theater, 1987-1988; 274559 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Parzival by Tankred Dorst, 1990; 274560 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Parzival photograph, undated; 274561 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Parzival Photographs, undated; 274562 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Rescue, 1997; 274563 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Rescue gala performance, undated; 274564 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Shakespeare's Sonnets [source material], undated; 274565 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - A Solo Performance, 1975-1976; 274566 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - A Solo Performance photographs, 1976; 274567 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Spaceman program, 1976; 274568 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - The Sundance Kid is Beautiful, 2012; 274569 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Sunshine Superman, 1989; 274570 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Taormina Festival: Robert Wilson symposium, 1997; 274571 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - A Tribute to Edwin Denby, 1997; 274572 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - T.S.E. come in under the shadow of this red rock, 1994; 274573 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - T.S.E. correspondence, 1994; 274574 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - T.S.E. correspondence with Change Performing Arts, 1996; 274575 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Two Nietsches in Love, 1989; 274576 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Videotape inventory list from The Kitchen, 1999-2000; 274577 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Watt, 1995; 274578 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Watch Movies/Watt, 1995; 274579 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Windows II script, undated; 274580 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Wisdom of the King, undated; 274581 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Wanderlust Swirling Through My Brain script, undated; 274582 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Workshop Transcripts, undated; 274583 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Subseries B: Performance without Christopher Knowles, 274425
    - 119 Comments by Cindy, 274584 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Airport Piece, 1975; 274585 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Angie's Waltz, c. 1977; 274586 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Blah Blah Blah, 2001; 274587 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds Performances, 1972, undated; 274588 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Civil Wars Journal - American June '82 by S.K. Dunn, June 1982; 274589 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Civil Wars correspondence, 1983-1984; 274590 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - A Dialogue by Merce Cunningham and John Cage, 1980; 274591 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Program from Follies, undated; 274592 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Performance Programs, 1980, 1982; 274593 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Robert Wilson programs [1 of 2], 1970-2000; 274594 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Robert Wilson Programs [2 of 2], 1970-2000; 274803 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Tribute to Anthology Film Archives, 1977; 274595 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Union Specific by Cindy Lubar, 1980; 274596 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Unattributed Scripts, undated; 274597 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Watermill/Persephone, 1995, 1998, undated; 274598 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Series III: Exhibitions, 274422
  This series is arranged chronologically with undated material at the end.
  This series contains material relating to Christopher Knowles' exhibitions of his artwork. This includes joint and solo exhibitions. The artwork exhibited includes paintings and "typings." The material includes publicity, catalogs, invitations, and photographs as well as some press and correspondence.
  - Dessins et Sculptures, 1974; 274599 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Schedule for The Kitchen, 1976; 274600 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Grant Applications submitted by Christopher Knowles, 1976-1982; 274601 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Drawing Center Exhibit, 1977; 274602 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Franklin Furnace exhibit, 1977; 274603 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Patterning and Decoration at Museum of the American Foundation for the Arts, 1977; 274604 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Summer/77 at the Drawing Center, 1977; 274605 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - About Earths and Universes at Holly Solomon Gallery, 1978; 274606 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Holly Solomon Gallery and Drawing Center photographs, 1978; 274607 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Sorcerer's Apprentice Machine Assisted Art, May 12, 1978-June 14, 1978; 274608 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Typing Work, 1978; 274609 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Red and Green: Paintings, Drawings and Audiotapes, 1979; 274611 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Red and Green Show photographs, 1979; 274612 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Stage Show at MoMA, March 5, 1979 - May 29, 1979; 274610 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Words and Images at the Philadelphia College of Art, 1979; 274613 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Artists and Models Ball: A benefit for Artists Space, 1980; 274614 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Hallwall: Emblems and Paint, 1980; 274615 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Holly Solomon Gallery: Three More, 1980; 274616 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - List of Exhibitions, 1980; 274617 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Visual Diaries: A Personal Use of Words and Images, 1980; 274618 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Art on Paper at the Weatherspoon Art Gallery, 1981; 274619 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The Destroyed Print, November 15, 1982 - December 11, 1982; 274620 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Drawing Center Exhibit, 1982; 274621 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Application for Institute for Art & Urban Resources, 1984; 274622 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Herman Costa "Booth" Installation, 1984; 274623 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Museum Boymans van Beuningen, 1985; 274625 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Shipment records from Museum Boymans exhibit, 1985; 274627 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Tekeningen en Typings [Museum Boymans publicity cards], 1985; 274632 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Holly Solomon Gallery Correspondence, 1985-1989; 274636 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Galerie Dorrie & Priess "Typings", 1988; 274641 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Robert Wilson's Vision, 1991; 274643 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - La Tradicion: Performing Painting, 1997; 274645 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Christopher Knowles Artwork Sales, 1998; 274646 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - The End: An Independent Vision of Contemporary Culture, 2000; 274647 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - To Whom it May Concern, 2002; 274649 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Gavin Brown Delivery, April 23, 2004; 276356 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Christopher Knowles at Gavin Brown's Enterprise, June 2004; 274651 (Box 4, Folder 36a)
  - 4th Berlin Biennial for Contemporary Art, 2006; 274653 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "Confines. Pasajes de Las Artes Contemporaneas" at the IVAM, 2009; 277128 (Box 4, Folder 37a)
  - Material for unrealized Einstein on the Beach Exhibit, 2013; 274655 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Wynn Newhouse Awards Exhibition, 2013-2014; 274656 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - East Village gallery cards, undated; 274657 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Everyday Business: A Benefit Exhibition, undated; 274659 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Poetic Visions, undated; 274662 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Series IV: Art, 274426
  This series is arranged chronologically with undated material at the back.
  This series contains original art by Christopher Knowles. This includes drawings and typings as well as poetry and prose. Some of the material relates to completed works of art like his collaboration with Robert Wilson, "Dialog/Curious George," as well as a few pieces that were exhibited in galleries. However, the majority of the material exists independently and should not necessarily be considered complete artworks.
  - Assorted Drawings & Typings, 1971, 1991-1994, undated; 274667 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Father's Day Art, 1973, undated; 274669 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Typewritten play inspired by Letter for Queen Victoria, 1974; 274672 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Andy Degroat and Dancers program, 1977; 274676 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Copyright agreement for unknown piece, 1977; 274740 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - New Yorker poetry submission, 1977; 274741 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Traveler's Digest "Letter to Paris", 1977; 274742 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Equipment manuals, 1978, undated; 274743 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - "Once Upon a Time" by Christopher Knowles, 1980; 274744 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "Artifacts at the End of a Decade", 1981; 274745 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Poetic Visions Playing Cards, 1981; 276357 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Artdates engagement calendar [1 of 2], 1984-1986; 274746 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Artdates engagement calendar [2 of 2], 1984-1986; 274747 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Photos & slides of Knowles paintings, 1984-1994; 274751 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Calendar typings, 1985; 274752 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - "History of My Memories", 1988; 274755 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Photography and framing services for Knowles' paintings, 1989-1992; 274757 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Photographs & photocopies of Knowles' paintings, 1989, 1990-1993, undated; 274760 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Photographs of Parzival paintings, 1990, undated; 274764 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Observations of Christopher Makos' opening preview, 1992; 274766 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Christmas party invite, 1995; 274768 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - [Sketches/outsider art], 2002; 276358 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Birthday invitations, 2004-2014, undated; 274770 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Lower Manhattan Map Project, 2007; 274771 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - MoMA Calendar, 2010; 274773 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Art Collection Short Form Files, undated; 274802 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Audio Work, undated; 274806 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Color & B/W photocopies of Knowles' paintings, undated; 274804 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Drawing of Simon Game, undated; 274807 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Drawing of the Earth, undated; 274808 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten list of song titles, undated; 274810 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Happy 15th Birthday Emily, undated; 274812 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Publicity photographs of WABC DJs [source material], undated; 274813 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Uncredited napkin art, undated; 274816 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Chart scroll, undated; 275113 (Box 10)
- Series V: Correspondence, 274427
  This series contains correspondence both sent and received by Christopher Knowles. It includes many cards and post cards, as well as professional correspondence concerning the exhibition and sale of his artwork, arranging performances and travel. There is correspondence between him and his parents, Jasper Johns, Jay Moses, Robert Wilson, Cindy Lubar and the Holly Solomon Gallery.
  - Lettres francaises, 1971; 274823 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence recieved by Knowles [1 of 2], 1972-1997; 274824 (Box 5, Folder 11)